Guide to the Goodrich Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Authors and publishers; Congregational churches -- Connecticut; Copyright -- United States; Education; English language -- Dictionaries; Families; Husband and wife; Land titles -- Indiana; Law and literature; Literature -- History and criticism; Durham (Conn.: Town); Europe -- Description and travel; New England; New Haven (Conn.); Deeds; Inventories; Memoirs; Patents (land); Sermons; Wills; Clergy; Educators; Lawyers; Lexicographers; Coe, Noah, 1786-1871; Converse, Sherman, 1790-1873; Ellsworth, Henry Leavitt, 1791-1858; Ellsworth, William Wolcott, 1791-1868; Ford, Emily Ellsworth Fowler, 1826-1893; Fowler, William Chauncey, 1793-1881; Goodrich, Chauncey A. (Chauncey Allen), 1790-1860; Goodrich, Chauncey, 1759-1815; Goodrich, Chauncey, 1817-1868; Goodrich, Elizabeth Ely Coe, 1821-1885; Goodrich, Elizur, 1734-1797; Goodrich, Elizur, 1761-1849; Goodrich, Julia Webster, 1793-1869; Goodrich, William H. (William Henry), 1823-1874; Merriam, Charles, 1806-1887; Webster, Noah, 1758-1843 ( American dictionary of the English language); Webster, Rebecca Greenleaf, 1760-1842; Goodrich family; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1732-1878; Series I; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is arranged in two sections: General and Select.
  General is arranged in chronological order. Undated material is in Select and is arranged by the name of the correspondent.
  - General
    - 1732-1833 May 16, 1833 May 20 - 1834 July (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
    - 1835-1850 (Box 2, Folder 12-24)
    - 1851 - 1860 (Box 3, Folder 25-36)
    - 1861-1878, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 37-40)
  - Select
    - Coe, Noah and Elizabeth, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Fowler, William Chauncey and Emily Ellsworth Fowler Ford, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Goodrich, Chauncey Allen, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Goodrich, Julia, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Topical Files, 1746-1905; Series II; 1.75 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series is arranged by record type in five sections: Sermons, Lectures, Notebooks, Business Papers, and Miscellanea.
  - Sermons
    - Goodrich, Chauncey Allen, 1815-1852, undated (Box 5, Folder 49-53)
    - Goodrich, Chauncey (1817-1868), 1844-1865, undated (Box 5, Folder 54-55)
    - Goodrich, Elizur (1734-1797), 1756-1792, undated (Box 6, Folder 56-58)
  - Lectures
    - "Brown", undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - "Lecture on John Locke", 1810 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - "Subjects for composition Freshman class", 1834 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - "Notes on famous orators of the world", 1838, 1839, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - "Lectures on Revivals", 1840 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - "Notes of Lectures on Emphasis", 1840 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - "Lecture VI", 1842 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - "Lecture VII", [1842?] (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - "Lecture V", 1843, undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - "Sandwich Islands", [ca. 1850] (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - "English Orthography", 1855 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - "American Eloquence", undated (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - "Eloquence", undated (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - "English Composition", undated (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - "Language is the medium…", undated (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - "Lecture I", undated (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - "Lecture II", undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - "Lecture III", undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - "Lecture on Demosthenes", undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - "Lecture on Sentences", undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - "Lectures on the Pastoral Charge", undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - "Observations on Elocution", undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - "The Omniscience of God", undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - "Public Speaking", undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - "Reasoning", undated (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - "Sensations", undated (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - "Language III", undated (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - "Lectures on Eloquence", undated (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - "Miscellaneous Notes", undated (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Notebooks
      - Goodrich, Chauncey (1759-1815), 1805-1807 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      - Goodrich, Chauncey (1817-1868): notebook of Yale College compositions, 1833-1836 (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - Goodrich, Chauncey Allen
        - Diary, 1840-1848 (Box 8, Folder 90)
        - Sermon notebook, undated (Box 8, Folder 91)
        - Travel diary, 1826 (Box 8, Folder 92)
        - Lexicography notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Coe, Charles Goodrich: Dwight's law lectures, vol. 3 and 4, [ca. 1867] (Box 8, Folder 94-95)
    - Coe, Noah: city missions journal and memoir, 1845-1864 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Whittlesey, Henry: Chinese puzzle, undated (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Business Papers, 1743-1875, undated (Box 9, Folder 98-103)
    General note
    See also: boxes 10 and 11
  - Miscellanea
    - Certificates and photographs, 1792, 1825, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 104)
      See also: box 10 box 11
    - Fragments, undated (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Genealogy, [ca. 1836-1868] (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Poems, undated (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Printed material, 1830-1905, undated (Box 9, Folder 108-109)
- Oversize
  - Goodrich, Elizur (1761-1849): deed, 1816 (Box 10)
    Folio
  - Goodrich, Chauncey Allen: certificates for purchase of public lands in Indiana, 1836-1838 (Box 10)
  - Yale bond, 1856 (Box 10)
  - Ellsworth, Henry L.: records of miscellaneous military grants for land in Indiana, 1848-1860 (Box 11)
  - ALS from Edward A. [Elves?] to Chauncey Goodrich (1817-1868), 1833 (Box 12)
  - Indentures, deeds, 1811, 1815, 1863 (Box 12)
  - Broadside: "Noah Webster: 'The Schoolmaster of the Republic", 1876 (Box 12)